

# Stephen G. McMillen 45200 Deep Canyon Rd. Apt. C5 Palm Desert, CA 92260 Phone: (760) 851-9267 / FAX: (760) 772-1316

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

StephenGMcMillen@Gmail.com

Responsible administrator, accountant & bookkeeper with excellent communication skills demonstrated by seven years of experience with personal, business, and nonprofit financial reporting in professional full-service accounting firms. Familiar with performing administrative functions and support for multiple professionals. Proficient at streamlining projects and client interaction.

## PROFESSIONAL GOALS

To secure a position in which further growth and education are possible, and where problem solving, creativity, and streamlining are applied. Professional certification goals include attaining an Enrolled Agent certification, and ultimately Certified Public Accountant certification.

## **JOB HISTORY**

03/2015 to present

Barton CPA
Palm Springs, CA

Administrative Assistant/Bookkeeper/Accountant

**Duties:** New employee training & on boarding. Processing of Corporate/Individual/Fiduciary/NPO

tax returns. Preparation of quarterly & annual payroll taxes. Preparation of monthly Marijuana Excise Tax returns. Bookkeeping, data entry, accounting, & controllership functions of cash basis & accrual basis financials. Administrative functions, client relations,

marketing & social media.

**Accomplishments**: Streamlined multiple bookkeeping projects, reducing completion time by an average of 30%.

Produced, shot, and edited one of the nation's top 20 QuickBooks 2015 Firm of the Future

videos.

01/2010 to present

Champion Income Tax Palm Desert, CA

Administrative Assistant/ Consulting Bookkeeper & Accountant

**Duties:** Bookkeeping & financial reporting. New client acquisition. Administrative functions, client

relations, marketing & social media.

**Accomplishments:** Increased accounting clients by 41%

Managed website & Yelp configuration & content.

Wrote & directed TV commercial for air.

#### Stephen G. McMillen

45200 Deep Canyon Rd. Apt. C5, Palm Desert, CA 92260

Phone: (760) 851-9267 / FAX: (760) 772-1316 / Email: StephenGMcMillen@Gmail.com

10/2014 to 3/2015

Proper Solutions Staffing Inc.

Indian Wells, CA

Staffing Agent

**Duties:** Interviewing & placing candidates based on job skills. Correspondence with hiring managers

and businesses to fill temporary and permanent positions.

12/2011 to 4/2013

KESQ News Channel 3 Palm Desert, CA

Master Control Operator

**Duties:** Recording, routing, downloading, ingesting, and trimming programs. Ensuring video / audio

quality was up to broadcast standards. Working with producers to broadcast live news.

### **EDUCATION**

#### 2005 - 2015

College of the Desert Film studies / Advertising

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

2016 California Tax Education Council (CTEC) certification.

15 years experience with Microsoft Office Suite: Word/Excel/PowerPoint.

5 years experience & proficiency with accounting software: Xero, QuickBooks Online & Desktop.

11 years video editing experience and proficiency in Final Cut, Vegas, & After Effects software.

7 years experience in graphic design and proficiency in Adobe Creative Software Suite.

5 year experience in audio editing.

## **AFFILIATIONS**

Desert Business Association - Member & Diplomat Palm Desert Chamber of Commerce - Member

Further employment experience & references available upon request.